A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Cultural Interests, Series E FA314
Rockefeller Archive Center
- French Restorations
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Welles Bosworth Correspondence, 1923-1932 (Box 140, Folder 1226)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. asks Bosworth to find out restoration requirements for Versailles, Rheims Cathedral, and Fontainebleau. Formation of Committee, with Bosworth a member as John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s representative. Bosworth's reports on meeting, progress of the work, problems of fluctuating francs and workmen; Bosworth's trip to Egypt to help Dr. James Breasted; his 1925 article on restorations. Work at Cite Universitaire. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in government effort to purchase Hotel des Reservoirs; his desire to terminate his obligations by January 1, 1936. Steps taken to induce French to continue the work; decisions regarding allocation of surplus funds. Various honors for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Disbanding of Committee. Bosworth paid $100,000, 1924-1936. Some later correspondence. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Welles Bosworth.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Welles Bosworth Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 140, Folder 1227)
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Welles Bosworth Correspondence, 1936-1958 (Box 140, Folder 1228)
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Welles Bosworth Correspondence, 1936-1958 (Box 140, Folder 1228A)
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts, 1933-1961 (Box 140, Folder 1229)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd wrote analysis of gifts to France in 1933 and gave John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a statement on conditions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - Tablet and Inscription, 1928-1940 (Box 140, Folder 1230)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. discouraged a tribute to himself on tablet but was willing to have a tablet erected as the gift of America to France. French decision to erect tablet mentioning John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s name. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Welles Bosworth.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - H. F. Sheets, 1923-1936 (Box 140, Folder 1231)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. worked out his early interest in this restoration through Sheets, who worked for Standard Oil in Paris. Details of gift, purpose and procedure. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. F. Sheets, Welles Bosworth.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - Articles on Work, 1925-1933 (Box 140, Folder 1232)
    "Revue des Deux Mondes" by G. Hanotaux on restoration, 1925. Also Paul Leon's "Remarks," 1933.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - 1924 Pledge (Box 140, Folder 1233)
    $1,000,000 gift.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - Rockefeller Brothers Fund Gift of 1953, 1952-1955 (Box 141, Folder 1234)
    For repairs at Versailles.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - Rockefeller Brothers Fund Gift of 1953, 1952-1955 (Box 141, Folder 1234A)
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - 1927 Pledge (Box 141, Folder 1235)
    40,000,000 francs.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - Gift of Steel Coffer, 1927 (Box 141, Folder 1236)
    Coffer with dirt from Belleau Woods given to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - French Restorations - Restorations in France - Gifts - Robert W. Gumbel Memos Regarding Gifts, 1930-1946 (Box 141, Folder 1237)
    Running statement of pledge amounts.
  - French Restorations - Gift to France - Letters of Appreciation, 1924-1946 (Box 141, Folder 1238)
    From French and Americans. Some appeals for aid, declined.
  - French Restorations - Memberships in French Societies, 1924-1934 (Box 141, Folder 1239)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined invitations to become member of several French societies; was made an honorary citizen of Versailles, member of Institut de France.
  - French Restorations - Memberships in French Societies - Union Interalliée, 1927-1960 (Box 141, Folder 1240)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a life member.
  - French Restorations - Memberships in French Societies - Union Interalliée, 1927-1960 (Box 141, Folder 1240A)
  - French Restorations - Comite Franco-Americain - Arthur Woods Correspondence, 1924-1927 (Box 141, Folder 1241)
    Details and procedures of gift to France; plans of restoration; work progress. Franco-American relations; war-debt significance of gift. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Robert W. Gumbel, J. Jusserand.
  - French Restorations - Comite Franco-Americain - Arthur Woods Correspondence, 1928-1936 (Box 141, Folder 1242)
  - French Restorations - Comite Franco-Americain - Equitable Trust Company, Chase, 1924-1936 (Box 141, Folder 1243)
    Purchase of francs; handling of funds in France. Interest payments. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, B. Turnbull.
  - French Restorations - Gift to France - Newspaper Articles and Booklets, 1924-1927 (Box 142, Folder 1244)
  - French Restorations - Gift to France - Newspaper Articles and Booklets, 1927-1930 (Box 142, Folder 1245)
  - French Restorations - Gift to France - Newspaper Articles and Booklets, 1924-1929 (Box 142, Folder 1246)
  - French Restorations - Chartres Cathedral, 1928-1956 (Box 142, Folder 1247)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. offers to help in restoring cleristory windows at Chartres; discussion of style of windows and glass. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. desire that windows reproduce 13th century style. 1934 decision to abandon work because of interpretive difficulties. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Welles Bosworth.
    188.1
  - French Restorations - Chartres Cathedral - Etienne Houvet, 1930-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1248)
    Caretaker of cathedral. Personal problems; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts.
  - French Restorations - Citizen of Versailles Certificate (Folder 1)
- Colonial Williamsburg
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General
    Planning, mapping, assembling historical data, property purchases, dealings with townspeople. Historical manuscripts, photos, printed items regarding Virginia colonial history and early Williamsburg. Acquisition of mace for House of Burgesses. National Park Service; radio broadcasts; Williamsburg contributions to other organizations. Junior Chamber of Commerce report on city problems; anti-semitism and anti-negro sentiment. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Charles O. Heydt, Arthur Woods, Vernon Geddy, Thomas M. Deveboise, Kenneth Chorley, Robert Lecky, William A. R. Goodwin, W. Perry, Phillip Keebler, Robert W. Gumbel.
    - Colonial Williamsburg - General, 1926-1928 (Box 143, Folder 1250)
    - Colonial Williamsburg - General, 1929-1934 (Box 143, Folder 1251)
    - Colonial Williamsburg - General, 1934-1940 (Box 143, Folder 1252)
    - Colonial Williamsburg - General, 1940-1950 (Box 143, Folder 1253)
    - Colonial Williamsburg - General, 1951-1956 (Box 143, Folder 1254)
    - Colonial Williamsburg - General, 1957-1961 (Box 143, Folder 1255)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Bells Hospital, 1951-1952 (Box 144, Folder 1256)
    Colonial Williamsburg's gift to aid hospital.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Frank Bliley and Edward Bliley, 1943-1945 (Box 144, Folder 1257)
    Blileys drove John D. Rockefeller, Jr. between Richmond and Williamsburg.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Bruton Heights School, 1950 (Box 144, Folder 1258)
    Unveiling of plaque honoring Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Churchill Visit and Dinner, April 1946, 1946-1949 (Box 144, Folder 1259)
    Plans for visit by Winston Churchill; toast by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; letters of appreciation.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Warrington Dawson, 1930-1935 (Box 144, Folder 1260)
    Publication of book on the Williamsburg reconstruction; research in France for materials to aid reconstruction; J. Gough's review of Dawson's book.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Duke of Gloucester Street Purchases, 1927 (Box 144, Folder 1261)
    Goodwin's gratitude to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; policy regarding purchases of property owned by Negroes.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Golf Course, 1928-1947 (Box 144, Folder 1262)
    Acquisition of land; plans, construction, operation.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Elizabeth Hayes, 1927-1940 (Box 144, Folder 1263)
    Salary arrangements; rental of Galt House; employment by American Red Cross.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Mary A. Lindsley, 1930-1948 (Box 144, Folder 1264)
    Manager of Williamsburg Inn, 1932-1937; hiring; relationship with the Rockefellers; success as a manager.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Prelude to Democracy, May 18, 1951, 1951-1952 (Box 144, Folder 1265)
    Celebration of 175th anniversary of independence. George Mason's Bill of Rights; exhibit of portraits and documents.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - 25th Anniversary Celebration, 1951 (Box 144, Folder 1266)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s authorization to Dr. Goodwin to purchase property; agenda, congratulations.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - 250th Anniversary Celebration, 1951 (Box 144, Folder 1267)
    Anniversary of Williamsburg's becoming Virginia Colonial capital.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Negro Church Consolidation, 1949-1954 (Box 144, Folder 1268)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. proposed to give money to three Negro churches with provision for consolidation and deed to Colonial Williamsburg; rejection of plan by churches; subsequent acceptance by one church.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Office Space in Goodwin Building, 1950 (Box 144, Folder 1269)
    Submission of plans regarding space for John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Colonial Williamsburg staff; effect on space given to Institute of Early American History and Culture.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Virginia Gazette, 1930-1955 (Box 144, Folder 1270)
    Unsuccessful attempts to purchase property.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Medical Care, 1955-1956 (Box 144, Folder 1271)
    Hospital services for Williamsburg; Winthrop Rockefeller's interest, contributions.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Zoning, 1934-1954 (Box 144, Folder 1272)
    Ordinance governing and defining buildings, alleys, garages, etc.; administration of colonial area (with comments, marginal notes).
  - Colonial Williamsburg - General - Virginia's 350th Anniversary, 1957-1959 (Box 144, Folder 1273)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Admission, 1934-1954 (Box 145, Folder 1274)
    Admission charges and fees; policy regarding use of passes and permits; statistics on paid admissions; pass privileges of Rockefellers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Kenneth Chorley, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Vernon Geddy, B. W. Norton.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Army and Navy Activities, 1942-1953 (Box 145, Folder 1275)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s concern over effect of nearby naval base on Williamsburg; cooperation of Williamsburg with service authorities in indoctrination program in American democratic ideals; use of Bassett Hall tower as observation for A.A. defense; concern over housing shortage. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, Vernon Geddy, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Army and Navy Activities - Visits from Soldiers, 1941-1943 (Box 145, Folder 1276)
    Letters of appreciation from soldiers regarding educational and inspirational value of Williamsburg visit. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, General Williford.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Army and Navy Activities - USO Building, 1942-1951 (Box 145, Folder 1277)
    Outfitting servicemen's recreation center; separate provisions for Negroes. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, Otto Lentz.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Army and Navy Activities - Dinner to Captain Ware, 1944 (Box 145, Folder 1278)
    Dinner to Captain Ware, United States Navy, given by Colonial Williamsburg trustees, May 2, 1944. Kenneth Chorley's speech introducing John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s speech.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Army and Navy Activities - Disposition of Surplus Property, 1944-1953 (Box 145, Folder 1279)
    Talks with government agencies to determine proper disposal of Camp Peary as surplus.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Army and Navy Activities - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Commitment, 1942-1946 (Box 145, Folder 1280)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Association for Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, 1933-1951 (Box 145, Folder 1281)
    Meeting notices, publications, booklets. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Mrs. Arthur Wilmer.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Williamsburg Awards, 1955-1961 (Box 146, Folder 1282)
    Discussion of policy of giving awards. Award to Winston Churchill, 1955. Winthrop Rockefeller address; Kenneth Chorley's account of trip to England. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. objection to the idea of awards. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Winthrop Rockefeller.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Williamsburg Awards - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1955 (Box 146, Folder 1283)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall, 1927-1940 (Box 146, Folder 1284)
    Purchase of property; construction, furnishing and landscaping; cost of Restoration. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, Elton Holland, Sven Janniche.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall, 1941-1953 (Box 146, Folder 1285)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall, 1954-1958 (Box 146, Folder 1285A)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Heating and Air Conditioning, 1937-1943 (Box 146, Folder 1286)
    Solving boiler, heating and air conditioning problems.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Heating and Air Conditioning, 1944-1949 (Box 147, Folder 1287)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Boat House and Boats, 1942-1952 (Box 147, Folder 1288)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Smith Guest House, 1931-1944 (Box 147, Folder 1289)
    Rescinding of original agreement granting life tenure to Bassett Hall to two ladies.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Rental Agreement, 1936-1941 (Box 147, Folder 1290)
    Lease agreement renting Bassett Hall to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Landscaping and Planting, 1931-1954 (Box 147, Folder 1291)
    Horticultural and financial details.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Budget, 1941-1958 (Box 147, Folder 1292)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest; rental of York Street properties.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - June 23, 1948 Gift to John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1948-1954 (Box 147, Folder 1293)
    Gift, subject to a life estate to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., of Bassett Hall, woodland areas, properties along York Street.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Property Program, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1294)
    Planned purchasing of property adjacent to Bassett Hall.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - May 1952 Agreement Regarding Disposition of Property Within Restored Area (Box 147, Folder 1295)
    Agreement not to dispose of land without conveying it to Colonial Williamsburg, Inc.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Mr. and Mrs. Folke Ahrbjorn - Personal, 1943-1952 (Box 147, Folder 1296)
    Caretaker and cook for Bassett Hall; close employer-employee relationship. Purchase of annuity for Ahrbjorns, payment of their doctor and hospital bills.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Correspondence Regarding Dam Construction, 1941-1946 (Box 147, Folder 1297)
    Impounding water to form Bassett Hall lake; construction of other dams. Tests to determine flow and run-off; costs. Correspondents include Arthur B. Miller, A. E. Kendrew, C. V. Lavery, H. O. Beebe, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Incorporation and Dissolution, 1942 (Box 147, Folder 1298)
    Dissolution of Bassett Hall, Inc., with transfer of property back to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Philipp Keebler, J. Duncan, Vernon Geddy, V. Webb, I. L. Jones, Kenneth Chorley, Duncan Cocke.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - Incorporation, 1938-1942 (Box 147, Folder 1299)
    Incorporation of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Bassett Hall properties; conveyance of property of Williamsburg Restoration, Inc. to Bassett Hall, Inc.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.s Payments, 1937-1946 (Box 148, Folder 1300)
    Rent to Bassett Hall, Inc. and expenses incurred in maintenance of the properties. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, I. L. Jones.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Bassett Hall - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1960-1961 (Box 148, Folder 1301)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd assumes responsibility for Bassett Hall after John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s death. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Williamsburg - Bruton Parish Church and Property, 1928-1960 (Box 148, Folder 1302)
    Negotiations for sale of property to Restoration; interior restoration of church; rededication service. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gift for new organ; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge in memory of Vernon Geddy. Correspondents include William A. R. Goodwin; Nelson A. Rockefeller, Kenneth Chorley, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Robert Lecky, Jr., J. Duncan.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Williamsburg - Bruton Parish Church and Property, 1928-1960 (Box 148, Folder 1303)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Capitol - General Assembly of Virginia Meetings, 1934-1936 (Box 148, Folder 1304)
    Meetings of the Virginia Legislature at Williamsburg, 1934, 1936, 1938, 1940, 1942; journals of sessions; invitations to speakers and members of the Rockefeller family to attend. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's invitation to General Assembly to hold joint assembly in Capitol at Williamsburg. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, G. Peery.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Capitol - General Assembly of Virginia Meetings, 1938-1948 (Box 149, Folder 1305)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Capitol - General Assembly of Virginia Meetings, 1950-1958 (Box 149, Folder 1306)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Capitol and Governors Palace, 1928-1933 (Box 149, Folder 1307)
    Excavation of old foundations; research on Capitol; altercation with APVA on reconstruction. Furnishing, paving, landscaping; congratulations for work done. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert Lecky, Arthur Woods, Charles O. Heydt, A. Kendrew, Kenneth Chorley.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Capitol and Governors Palace, 1934-1957 (Box 149, Folder 1308)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Capitol and Governors Palace - Capitol Parking Area, 1953 (Box 149, Folder 1309)
    Rejection of proposal to provide temporary parking area. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. Kendrew.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence, 1929-1935 (Box 149, Folder 1310)
    Memos on purchase and maintenance of property; offers to sell and purchase equipment; laws affecting city; sale of Goodwin's book. Administrative problems, expenses, income, investment of funds; educational programs, accounting procedures, Negro housing project. Airport location, construction program, exhibits; report on landscaping problems. Policy regarding purchase of manuscripts, documents, maps and books; wartime labor conditions. Correspondents include Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, Vernon Geddy, Charles O. Heydt, Horace Albright.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 149, Folder 1311)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 150, Folder 1312)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 150, Folder 1313)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 150, Folder 1314)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence - Coaches, Guides, Uniforms, 1929-1940 (Box 150, Folder 1315)
    Education of guides, selection of uniforms, restoration of coaches, purchase of horses.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence - Volume - History of Restoration, 1933, 1941-1944 (Box 150, Folder 1316)
    Preparation by Dr. Goodwin and Miss Hayes of "The Williamsburg Restoration: Its Conception," with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s comments.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence - Volume - History of Restoration, 1953-1959 (Box 150, Folder 1317)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley Correspondence - Kenneth Chorley Retirement, 1958 (Box 150, Folder 1318)
    Announcement; tributes. Newsclippings, praise. Carlisle H. Humelsine his successor.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Christopher Wren Building, 1926-1929 (Box 151, Folder 1319)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agrees to finance preliminary study of possibility of restoration. Estimated costs, construction, insurance; acceptance by College. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William A. R. Goodwin, Charles O. Heydt, Robert Lecky, Jr., Arthur Woods, Kenneth Chorley, F. Christy, Thomas M. Debevoise, W. Perry, J. Chandler.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Christopher Wren Building, 1930-1933, 1945 (Box 151, Folder 1320)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Christopher Wren Building - Cost of Repairs Agreements, 1928-1931 (Box 151, Folder 1321)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Colonial National Monument and Parkway, 1939-1959 (Box 151, Folder 1322)
    Approach to tunnel; devices to expedite access to Williamsburg from Parkway; land purchases; gift to National Park Service. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer, Kenneth Chorley, Vernon Geddy, Horace Albright.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Colonial National Monument and Parkway, 1937-1939 (Box 151, Folder 1323)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Colonial National Monument and Parkway - Construction of Jamestown, 1940-1954 (Box 151, Folder 1324)
    Purchase of land between Parkway and James River.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Colonial National Parkway Tunnel, 1939-1943 (Box 151, Folder 1325)
    Engineering problems in digging tunnel; acquiring land from hospital for right of way; damage to gardens, relocation of sewers, resurfacing roads; postwar obstacles to completion. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer, Kenneth Chorley, R. Drury.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Eastern State Hospital, 1934-1953 (Box 152, Folder 1326)
    Removal of hospital from Williamsburg. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, Thomas M. Debevoise, Vernon Geddy, John S. Bryan, Winthrop Rockefeller.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Eastern State Hospital, 1953-1959 (Box 152, Folder 1327)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Educational Project - Radio Program, 1940-1941 (Box 152, Folder 1328)
    Themes for possible educational programs; production of film. Correspondents include Archibald MacLeish, Julian Boyd, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Educational Project - Radio Program, 1942-1955, 1961 (Box 152, Folder 1329)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Educational Project - Radio Program Henry F. Carlton, 1941, 1947 (Box 153, Folder 1330)
  - Colonial Williamsburg - Employees, 1942-1949 (Box 152, Folder 1331)